<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: TMUX | My Octopress Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://JetFault.github.com/blog/categories/tmux/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://JetFault.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-10-14T21:28:29-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://JetFault.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Your Name]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My Recent Set-up]]></title>
    <link href="http://JetFault.github.com/blog/2012/10/04/my-recent-set-up/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-04T17:06:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://JetFault.github.com/blog/2012/10/04/my-recent-set-up</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My recent hacking set-up has changed quick differently with my VPS.
Rather than carrying my computer anywhere, I just SSH into it and store everything on it.
I never bring my laptop with me anymore, and the only reason I ever need it is to work on some Photoshop.
So first lets start out with the hardware I'm running.</p>

<h3>The Gamer</h3>

<p>I recently purchased a gaming laptop, Sager NP9150, for some Guild Wars 2 and CS:GO gaming.
I had a free key for Windows 8 from school and decided to test it out. No Wireless Drivers!
The laptop I was planning on bringing around and doing some gaming/coding at the computer lab became a desktop.
Windows 8 technically isn't out and I'm sure REALTEK will release drivers soon (but let's not look
at their track record with Linux). So I've never been a Windows fanboy, but its nice.
Hell I'm the President of the Rutgers University Student Linux User Group, I'm not allowed to use Windows.
The touch interface isn't that annoying to use without a touchscreen, for me its actually more intuitive.
The Live Tiles are really nice and sleek, and the facebook/twitter app is beautiful and simplistic.
But let's stop oogling over how Microsoft actually made a nice UX and get back ontopic. This laptop only
runs Windows, so all it does is: Photoshop, Chrome, Guild Wars 2, Spotify. I haven't used Windows in years
and I found myself getting annoyed at doing anything but the above. I was browsing the chrome store and
found that Google had a SSH client, Secure Shell. Add to Chrome!
My environment was back! My tmux, my vim, my bash, my node! It was all under my fingertips, in WINDOWS!
By the way, right click on Secure Shell and check, open in window, this lets you be able to use Ctrl-W.
From this moment I noticed that I was the exact user that ChromeOS was looking for. I received the
beta CR-48 when it came out from Google on my doorstep a couple days before Christmas. Back then, I was
not a ChromeOS user. Everything in the browser? How about my apps?! What if I need Eclipse? (I didn't
know vim back then) I'm actually thinking of reviving my Chromebook (sad face on boot) and adding it
to my set-up. Now that my entire hacking life lives on a server and github, why do I need one machine;
I need many, everywhere. This is my machine in my dorm.</p>

<h3>The Lemon</h3>

<p>My older computer is a 3 year old Dell Studio XPS16 that overheats like a mother and only has 1.5 hours
of battery.
So this computer is anything but portable, requiring me to bring a charger and cooler with me everywhere I go.
But, this is the computer I would take with me if I ever needed something portable.
It's running Windows 7 and Ubuntu 12.04, more than 90% on Ubuntu. This is my main hacking computer.
I have my LAMP, Redis, Node, Ruby, and a bunch of Chef &amp; Amazon scripts. The lid is defaced with all the
stickers I got from hackathons, a true hacker's computer. But recently, it has been seeing less and less
terminals and hacking. I am usually in two places: my dorm or the computer lab. If I'm in my dorm I use
my new laptop and if I'm at the computer lab, then I use the machines there. Because my entire hacker
station is moving from a local entity to a remote one, I can hack on anything. I don't need my laptop,
I can use anything with an internet connection, even my phone!</p>

<p><img src="/images/laptop-sticker.jpg"></p>

<h3>The Cloud</h3>

<p>Over the summer, I worked at a startup in NYC called <a href="http://www.peek.ly">Peek</a> as a DevOps Intern.
I would get a text that a machine is down while I'm out to lunch. Awknowledge the alert, open ConnectBot
on my Nexus, ssh into our server, restart the instance. This is where I got the idea of getting a VPS
and using it for access to everything. Later, I left my laptop at work and remembered that I had to commit
something. I didn't need my laptop, I was developing on the server, downloaded putty on my dad's computer,
took 10 minutes going through emails trying to find the IP, then commited. Damnit, where is my cloud!</p>

<p>This is when I noticed Chrome has spoiled me, same sessions everywhere I go, all my saved passwords,
all my chrome apps. I could have easily checked the IP on the AWS console, if I remembered the password.
I go through about 10 different machines on different networks a week. Go to class, open chrome, log in,
leave off where I stopped last class. Once I get out of class, open my tabs on my phone and read on the bus.</p>

<p>My VPS is from <a href="http://www.prgmr.com">prgmr</a> and I would definitely recommend them! I'm running Ubuntu 12.04,
nginx, and octopress for my blog. I just started working on my <a href="https://github.com/JetFault/dotfiles">dotfiles</a>
and want to add a bunch more. I also wanna work on some Chef or Puppet scripts to set up an ec2 instance
exactly how my VPS looks now, so make dotfiles for my entire machine :)</p>

<p>Thanks for reading and I do recommend you check out Secure Shell if you have the unfortunate pains of not
being in your hacker home.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
